Guide to the Southern Poverty Law Center Intelligence Project Collection, 1940s-2020; 1940s-ongoing RL.10135
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Documented Organizations, 1940s-2000s; 1
  - Vita-Mix Corporation, 303
    - Catalog, 1997 (Box 6)
  - Wiswell Ruffin House, 304
    - Catalogs, 1990-1992 (Box 6)
      Temecula
  - World Church of the Creator, 305
    - Literature, catalogs, 2000 and undated (Box 6)
      East Peoria
      Printout of "The Struggle," other materials.
  - World Service Library, 306
    - Literature, undated (Box 6)
      Pamphlet: "Kosher Racket Revealed."
  - World War 2 Books and Video, 307
    - Catalogs, 2000-2002 (Box 6)
      Monticello
  - Wotansvolk, 308
    - Literature, undated (Box 6)
      St. Maries
      "Focus Fourteen" issue no. 911.
  - Year 2000 Alert, 309
    - Literature, 1999 (Box 6)
      Palm Beach Gardens
      Pamphlets by Martin Weiss.
- SPLC Research, Subjects, Clippings, and Web Files, 1980s-2000s; 1980s-ongoing; 2
  - Clippings, 1990s-2000s; 1
    - Clippings collected by clippings services, 2003-2004 (Box 7)
      Conditions Governing Access note
      Loosely sorted by month/year.
      SPLC subscribed to clippings services to monitor news coverage of accusations of bias, hate crimes, Klan and Nazi activities, and mentions of other extremist groups. Clippings collected are from local and regional publications and do not include national press stories from AP or other syndicates.
    - Miscellaneous clippings, 1990s-2000s (Box 7)
      Includes clippings about various hate groups, racial discord, and coverage of SPLC.
  - Miscellaneous Literature, 1980s-2000s; 2
    - Miscellaneous Pro-Aryan/Pro-White, 1980s-2000s (Box 8)
      Includes various clippings, handouts, and fliers from neo-Nazis, Klan groups, and white power groups.
    - Miscellaneous Pro-America/Anti-Communist, 1980s-2000s (Box 8)
      Includes literature on anti-tax movements, anti-UN movements, etc.
    - Miscellaneous Pro-Christian/Pro-Israelite, 1980s-2000s (Box 8)
      Includes literature by pro-white Christian extremists.
    - Miscellaneous Racist, 1980s-2000s (Box 8)
      Majority of materials are anti-Black/anti-African American.
    - Miscellaneous Anti-Catholic, 1980s-2000s (Box 8)
    - Miscellaneous Anti-Semitic, 1980s-2000s (Box 8)
      Includes Holocaust deniers.
    - "The Enigma of Christian Hate", 1998-1999 (Box 8)
      Anonymous research article.
    - Beam, Louis, undated (Box 8)
      Excerpt of "Skinheads" from The Seditionist.
    - Griffin, Robert, 2004 (Box 8)
      Copy of "One Sheaf, One Vine," Griffin's self-published book.
    - Hammer, Thorz, 1990s (Box 8)
      Adkins
      Mass mailings from Thorz Hammer promoting his book "WHAM! Confessions of a White American Man."
    - Rimland, Ingrid, 1998 (Box 8)
      La Costa
      "Lebensraum" literature.
  - Research files, 1980s-2000s; 3
    - Index of Klan and Racist Publications, 1980s-2000s (Box 8)
      Created and annotated by SPLC. Incomplete.
    - "Identity Directory", 1980s (Box 8)
      Photocopy of Directory for "All Anglo-Saxon Celtic and Kindred Peoples," including organizations, contact names, and addresses for New Israelites from around the world.
    - Listing of Hate Groups, 2004 (Box 8)
      SPLC list of hate groups.
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1990s-2000s (Box 8)
      Unsolicited informant letters for SPLC.
  - Web Files, 2014-2020; 2014-ongoing
    - Southern Poverty Law Center website, 2014-2020; 2014-ongoing
    - Southern Poverty Law Center YouTube, 2020; 2020-ongoing